SAMANTHA SHARFF

Camden, ME | SamanthaLeeC@gmail.com | 603-617-6940 | github.com/SamSharff | linkedin.com/in/samsharff

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software engineer who thrives in the space where the public and tech interact. With boots-on-the-ground experience as a librarian and social service worker, I bring a track record for meticulous attention to detail and a deep commitment to user experience to my work as an engineer.

SKILLS

Technical: JavaScript, HTML, APIs, Ruby on Rails, Vue.js, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, Testing,

Pair-Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap

Additional: Microsoft Suite; Google Docs; CRM software; Member, Technologists for the Public Good

EDUCATION

Actualize Coding Bootcamp | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Jan 2022 - May 2022

A four-month full-stack web development bootcamp. Core technologies included Ruby, Rails,
JavaScript, HTML, and Vue.js. Special emphasis on API-driven development, version control with
GitHub, professional tooling, team collaboration, and continual learning.

University of Missouri | Coursework towards M.A. in Library and Information Science University of New Hampshire | B.A. in Theatre

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant (Web Development) | Actualize Coding Bootcamp

Jun 2022 - Current

- Lead virtual office hours for cohort of 14 students, triaging bugs, ensuring students understand key concepts, and providing additional instruction when necessary
- Facilitate student learning of Ruby, Rails, APIs, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, PostgreSQL and additional technical skills in live, intensive online classroom environment
- Evaluate student progress and comprehension in communication and partnership with lead software instructor

Office Manager | Rockland Congregational Church

Aug 2020 - Feb 2022

- Managed daily operations for 120+ member church, overseeing facilities and collaborating with leadership, members, and committees to keep things efficient and clean
- Modernized all business operations by digitizing records, automating manual processes via software, and documenting and training others in best technology practices to support the onboarding of future employees

AP Finance Contractor | Knox County Homeless Coalition

Apr 2020 - Oct 2020

- Implemented automation practices, data conventions, and digital platforms and software for an organization that was previously using manual record keeping
- Trained multiple departments on best practices for new financial systems, ensuring accurate accounts payable and credit card expense documentation during the pandemic
- Tracked data points related to state housing grant expenditures to support the continued proper administration of emergency money for sheltering the homeless and those at risk

Library Professional | Rockport Public Library, Norwich Public Library

Aug 2014 - Jun 2020

- Through daily use and research, achieved deep understanding of ILS platforms while taking graduate classes in Library and Information Science
- Troubleshot technology issues for users daily, identifying the source of errors and providing solutions
- Guided customers through all steps of creating, navigating, and troubleshooting library accounts and services
- Tracked and reported programming statistics to determine areas for improvement and optimization

Co-owner & Communications Contractor | Cobblestone Communications

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

- Produced copy, web design, social media, e-newsletter, and photographic services for nonprofits and small businesses by taking time to understand client goals and translating them into marketable materials
- Trained local business and nonprofit leaders on how to access and update their website designs and troubleshoot technical problems as they arose

Lead Caseworker | Episcopal Service Corps.

Sep 2012 - Jun 2013

- Evaluated client eligibility for requested services based on level of need and current available budget
- Partnered with organization Director to track and manage grants of up to \$50,000, maximizing benefit to clients while maintaining compliance with grant stipulations
- Promoted from intern to lead caseworker within three months of beginning service term

CERTIFICATIONS

Notary Public | State of Maine

Jan 2019

Public Librarian Certificate | Maine State Library

April 2017

Intro to Data Analysis Certificate | IBM, Coursera.org

Mar 2021